Guide to the Stanford University, Libraries, Physics Library, Crank File
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Libraries, Physics Library, crank file
1981-1990
SC0483
Stanford University. Libraries. Physics Library.
2 Linear feet
Correspondence, unsolicited manuscripts, pamphlets, and books received by the Physics Library or the Dept. of Physics; correspondents include students, faculty in other disciplines, and non-academic scientists, as well as the general public.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Administrative transfer.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Description of the Collection
Correspondence, unsolicited manuscripts, pamphlets, and books received by the Physics Library or the Dept. of Physics; correspondents include students, faculty in other disciplines, and non-academic scientists, as well as the general public.
Access Terms
Stanford University. Department of Physics.; Stanford University. Libraries. Physics Library.; Physics.
Collection Contents
- Papers, 1981-1990
  - Albright, Charles F. "An analysis of the postulated hyperforce (as it relates to) a unification of the four basic interactions", 1986 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Amundsen, Trond. "Mass, motion, energy, space and time", 1986; With letter (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Babcock, J.P., letter, Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Baker, Dorothy Gillam. "Climax of history: from turbulence to transformation", 1987 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Barzydlo, Arnold Hames. "Time and geometry: a unification of the strong and weak nuclear forces", 1987 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Blotkamp, Richard. "Does God play dice?" and "Spin-Charge Equivalency", 1983; With letter (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Bozhich, Serge. "Errors of modern science", 1990; With letter (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Breznick, Burton. "Efficacy of electronic and quantum circuits", 1985 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Brown, Louis, letter, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Chan, Kenneth K.C. "Time and space", 1989; With letter (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Chavan, S.S. "The theory of matter waves under review", 1989 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Ciocchi, Pedro N. "The physical space - a new logic", 1989 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Clark, William A., letter re: light waves, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Claudio, Victor. "A review of Newton's law of gravity", 1984 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Cramer, Marvin. "The full description of a point in space", 1990; Letter, computer printouts, and computer disk (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Cyr, Rev. Guy J. "Negative gravity is real"; "The shroud of Turin", 1986-1988 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Davidson, Glen. "Proposal for using different solutes in a common solvent to produce perpetual motion of the second kind", 1986 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Ehrensperger, Jakob. "Die expansion des kosmos; die expension der erde", 1984 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Eremia, G. Robert. Three statements on neutrinos, Higgs particle, and the superstring theory, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Fakhari, Mohsen. "Eventics; an introductory book; the foundation of the unified world", 1988 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Fazekas, Victor. "Are science and A. Einstein right?", 1987; With letters (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Ferreira, Keith. "My ontological development," "Inverse-space," and "The hidden variables of nature", 1985-1987; With letter (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Flannery, Margaret, letter re: Einstein and invention of atomic bomb, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Floberg, Leif. "The damage to the bearings of the earth (the big splash)", 1989 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Fortune, Albert. "Chance and the universe", Undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Frank, Michael, letters re: gravity, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Gadanac, Fredric. "Inherent and acquired equilibric duality in force field unification", 1990; With letter (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - George, Sebastian, letter re: "twin-paradox" and Einstein's special theory of relativity, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Gonzalez, Florentino R., letter re: energy equation, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Hall, Charles F., patent papers and letters re: his solid state thermoelectric power coupling, 1982-1985 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Harrington, Robert K., letter re: ESP, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Hawk, Erwin, letter re: the Lorentz transformation, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Hazra, Sankar, letter re: nuclear force and pamphlet "Light: an insight", 1984-1989 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Irvine, Dallas. "A challenging of traditional mathematics and special relativity", 1981 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Jeong, Moon. "Space tunnel hypothesis", 1990 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Ke-dong, Xiao, letter re: intersection of electric forces, Undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Korkmaz, H. Metin. "The cause of assimetric breaking of carrier elements in weak nuclear power", 1985; With letter (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Lawrence, R.P. "The simple universe", 1984; With letter (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Lydon, Marie, letter re: general physics, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - McAdam, William Lee, letter re: eradication of gonorrhea, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Meng, Shao. "The postulate of cosmic repulsion", 1986; With letter (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - M'Hamed, Rhayour, letter re: science and the Koran, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Miscellaneous and anonymous items, Undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Mizuki, Mikiso. "A simple quantum mechanics model I - a single particle" and "A simple quantum mechanics model II - a singlet pair experiments", 1984-1985; With letter (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Molinaro, Angelo A., letter, announcements, and ad re: his book The Two State Universe, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Morales, Juan. "Proofs of the non existence of the contraction of moving bodies", 1986 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Morgan, Raymond. "A universe of dimensions", 1985 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Morina, Lou. "Gravity theory", 1986 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Munoz, Alvaro A. "Luz=Tiempo", 1986; With letter (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Muraleedharakurup, R., letter re: general physics, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Neergard, John R. "Theory of restricted absolute motion", 1985-1987; With letters (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Newman, Joseph. "Superconductivity - the real truth", Circa 1987 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Nicholas, Georgiadis, letter re: observed phenomenon, Undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Payette, Frank, letter re: infinities and the speed of light, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Payne, L.D. "On the velocity of light", 1986 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Popal, Azimullah. "Modified special relativity", Undated; With letter (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Rider, E., letter re: free energy devices, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Rowland, Charles A. "Spiritual atomic truth", 1990; With letter (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Rozier, W.S. "A challenge to experimental scientists", 1984; Bound version (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Rozier, W.S. "A challenge to experimental scientists", 1984-1985; Supplements with letters (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Rozier, W.S. "A physical aether" and "Mass-energy-velocity relationships", 1988 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Sadighi, Kaveh, letter re: electromagnetic force generator, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Selig, Malca and Ronit, letter re: dangers of technology to planet's safety, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Slon, James. "Basic qualimatics", 1985 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Sokolow, Leonid. "The fifth force; supergravity and the dual ether theory" and "A proposal for testing the universal constancy of the speed of light in space during an orbital mission", 1984-1987 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Sourial, Alfy S., letter and paper on ether, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Stixrud, Jack W., letters re: nature of sunlight, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Thompson, Gordon A., letter of his ideas on the world, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Tomei, Lawrence, ideas of creating fusion and neutralizing radioactive waste, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Trotter D., letters on antiparticles, tachyons and unified field theory, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Tsolkas, Christos A., paper on verifying the theory of relativity, 1987; With letter (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Tsuru, Michi. "Supermass number theory", 1987 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Vallee, Rene Louis. "Synergetics", 1986 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Van Heerden, Pieter J. "Proposal for a fundamental theory of physics", 1988 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Windham, James, letter re: energy and matter, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Zamir, Yecheskiel. "Avkoan theory; volume 1", 1985 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Zhung, Ping-Dong. "Quantum collisons [sic] mechanics" and "Macrochemistry", 1985 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Books Received, Undated (Box 4)
    Alesky, Ronald. Life and Cosmos; Behling, Thomas. Introducing Life into Physics; Carroll, Robert L. The Energy of Physical Creation; Jacot, Louis. A Heretical Cosmology; Nicols, Herbert L, Jr. Science Blundering: an Outsider's View; Parker, Robert Hayward. In Search of a Unified Physics; Salem, Kenneth G. 2.8 Angstroms: The Unifying Force of G and c; Seike, Shinichi. The Principles of Ultra Relativity; Weiss, Richard A. Relativistic Thermodynamics, volumes 1 and 2.